Only Human: HIV-negative Gay Men in the AIDS Epidemic Archive 1995-1996 MSS.376
Fales Library and Special Collections
Only Human: HIV-negative Gay Men in the AIDS Epidemic Archive
1995-1996
Fales Library and Special Collections
Nitty Gritty Productions
DiFeliciantonio, Tina
Deitcher, David
Mookas, Ioannis
MSS.376
2 Linear Feet
Only Human: HIV-negative Gay Men in the AIDS Epidemic Archive is comprised of source material, work-in-progress sample reels, masters, and the final cut of the film "Only Human: HIV-negative Gay Men in the AIDS Epidemic. "Only Human: HIV-Negative Gay Men in the AIDS Epidemic" is a documentary that explores the relationship between HIV risk reduction practices and the advent of AIDS.
Historical note
"Only Human: HIV-Negative Gay Men in the AIDS Epidemic" is a documentary that explores the relationship between HIV risk reduction practices and the advent of AIDS. The documentary includes interviews that draw from the sexual experiences of HIV-negative men from a variety of backgrounds. "Only Human" simultaneously follows the dramatic struggle of one gay Latino youth's to balance health with sexuality.
Sources:
Turner Classic Movies, http://www.tcm.com/tcmdb/title/525285/Only-Human-HIV-Negative-Gay-Men-in-the-AIDS-Epidemic/
Internet Movie Database, http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0397588/plotsummary
Scope and Content
Only Human: HIV-negative Gay Men in the AIDS Epidemic Archive is comprised of source material, work-in-progress sample reels, masters, and the final cut of the film "Only Human: HIV-negative Gay Men in the AIDS Epidemic." The film was directed by Ioannis Mookas, written by David Deitcher, and co-produced by Mookas, Deitcher, and Tina DiFeliciantonio. The videorecordings span from 1995 to 1998.
The collection is arranged in one series:
Series I: Videorecordings: contains 2 boxes of VHS and Betacam SP.
Arrangement
Video recordings are arranged chronologically, when recordings are dated.
Related Material at Fales Library and Special Collections
The Mix Collection (MSS.143)
Nelson Sullivan Video Collection (MSS.357)
Gay Cable Network Archive (MSS.231)
Provenance
The Only Human: HIV-negative Gay Men in the AIDS Epidemic Archive was donated to Fales Library by David Deitcher, in September 2013.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Access copies for some materials are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Please contact fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Video recordings -- Social aspects.; Video recordings -- Political aspects; Gays -- Political activity -- New York (State) -- New York.; Videocassettes.; AIDS (Disease) and art -- United States.; AIDS (Disease) -- Social aspects -- New York (N.Y.); Film.; Gay men -- United States.; Sims, Neil; Fung, Alvin; Marer, Marcelo; Miller, Reggie; Blythe, Bernard; Sayed, Javid; MAPP, Derrick; Montoya-Montez, Andy; Diaz, Henry; Cordero, Carlos
- Series I: Video recordings
  General
  Audio levels modulate on some of these videos.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access copies for some materials are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Please contact fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
  - Only Human: Reel #1: Neil Sims, December 16, 1995; ID: 376.0001 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0001, Box Shared Fales 128, Dvd 376.0001)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Duration: 30 minutes
    Original format: VHS
    Existence and Location of Copies
    DVD access copy available.
    Currently available.
  - Only Human: Reel #2: Neil Sims, December 16, 1995; ID: 376.0002 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0002, Box Shared Fales 128, Dvd 376.0002)
  - Only Human: Reel #3: Neil Sims, December 16, 1995; ID: 376.0003 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0003, Box Shared Fales 128, Dvd 376.0003)
  - Only Human: Reel #4: Neil Sims, December 16, 1995; ID: 376.0004 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0004, Box Shared Fales 128, Dvd 376.0004)
  - Only Human: Reel #5: Carlos Cordero, December 16, 1995; ID: 376.0005 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0005, Box Shared Fales 128, Dvd 376.0005)
  - Only Human: Reel #6: Carlos Cordero, December 16, 1995; ID: 376.0006 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0006, Box Shared Fales 128, Dvd 376.0006)
  - Only Human: Reel #7: Carlos Cordero, December 16, 1995; ID: 376.0007 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0007, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0007)
  - Only Human: Reel #8: Carlos Cordero, December 16, 1995; ID: 376.0008 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0008, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0008)
  - Reel #9: Henry Diaz (Master), December 16, 1995; ID: 376.0009 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0009)
    Duration: unknown
    Original format: Betacam SP
    Currently unavailable until duplication occurs.
  - Only Human: Reel #9: Henry Diaz, December 16, 1995; ID: 376.0010 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0010, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0010)
  - Reel #10: Henry Diaz (Master), December 16, 1995; ID: 376.0011 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0011)
  - Only Human: Reel #10: Henry Diaz, December 16, 1995; ID: 376.0012 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0012, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0012)
  - Reel #11: Henry Diaz (Master), December 16, 1995; ID: 376.0013 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0013)
  - Only Human: Reel #11: Henry Diaz, December 16, 1995; ID: 376.0014 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0014, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0014)
  - Reel #12: Henry Diaz (Master), December 16, 1995; ID: 376.0015 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0015)
  - Only Human: Reel #12: Henry Diaz, 1995; ID: 376.0016 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0016, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0016)
  - Only Human: Reel #13: Andy Montoya-Montez, 1995; ID: 376.0017 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0017, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0017)
  - Only Human: Reel #14: Andy Montoya-Montez, 1995; ID: 376.0018 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0018, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0018)
  - Only Human: Reel #15: Andy Montoya-Montez, 1995; ID: 376.0019 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0019, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0019)
  - Gay Pride: Reel #20: Derrick MAPP, June 30, 1996 and July 1, 1996; ID: 376.0020 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0020, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0020)
  - Reel #21: Derrick MAPP, July 1, 1996; ID: 376.0021 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0021, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0021)
  - Reel #22: Derrick MAPP, July 1, 1996; ID: 376.0022 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0022, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0022)
  - Reel #23: Derrick MAPP, July 1, 1996; ID: 376.0023 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0023, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0023)
  - Reel #24: Derrick MAPP, July 1, 1996; ID: 376.0024 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0024, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0024)
  - Reel #25: 1. Derrick MAPP (Portrait) 2. Javid Sayed, July 1, 1996; ID: 376.0025 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0025, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0025)
  - Reel #26: Javid Sayed, July 1, 1996; ID: 376.0026 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0026, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0026)
  - Reel #27: Javid Sayed, July 1, 1996; ID: 376.0027 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0027, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0027)
  - Reel #28: Javid Sayed, July 1, 1996; ID: 376.0028 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0028, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0028)
  - Reel #29: 1. Javid Sayed 2. Bernnard Blythe, July 2, 1996; ID: 376.0029 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0029, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0029)
  - Reel #30: Bernard Blythe, July 2, 1996; ID: 376.0030 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0030, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0030)
  - Reel #31: Bernard Blythe, July 2, 1996; ID: 376.0031 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0031, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0031)
    Duration: 32 minutes
  - Reel #32: Bernard Blythe, July 2, 1996; ID: 376.0032 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0032, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0032)
    Duration: 31 minutes
  - Reel #33: 1. Bernard Blythe 2. Reggie Miller, July 2, 1996; ID: 376.0033 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0033, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0033)
  - Reel #34: Reggie Miller, July 2, 1996; ID: 376.0034 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0034, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0034)
    Duration: 29 minutes
  - Reel #35: Reggie Miller, July 2, 1996; ID: 376.0035 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0035, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0035)
  - Reel #36: 1. Reginald Miller 2. Marcelo Marer, July 2, 1996-July 3, 1996; ID: 376.0036 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0036, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0036)
  - Reel #37: Marcelo Marer, July 3, 1996; ID: 376.0037 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0037, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0037)
    Duration: 33 minutes
  - Reel #38: Marcelo Marer, July 3, 1996; ID: 376.0038 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0038, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0038)
  - Reel #39: Marcelo Marer, July 3, 1996; ID: 376.0039 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0039, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0039)
    Duration: 28 minutes
  - Reel #40: Alvin Fung, July 3, 1996; ID: 376.0040 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0040, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0040)
  - Reel #41: Alvin Fung, July 3, 1996; ID: 376.0041 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0041, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0041)
  - "Only Human" Sample Video (Master), March 2, 1996; ID: 376.0042 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0042)
  - Only Human: Work in Progress Reel (Protection Master), September 1, 1996; ID: 376.0043 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0043)
  - Only Human: HIV-negative gay men in the AIDS epidemic work-in-progress sample reel, undated; ID: 376.0044 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0044, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0044)
    Duration: 11 minutes
    Original format: 3/4" Umatic
  - Only Human: HIV-negative gay men in the AIDS epidemic work-in-progress sample reel, undated; ID: 376.0045 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0045, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0045)
    Duration: 12 minutes
  - Only Human: HIV-negative gay men in the AIDS epidemic (complete), 1998; ID: 376.0046 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0046, Box Shared Fales 127, Dvd 376.0046)
    Duration: 58 minutes